<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Gautham Narayan</title>
    <link>https://gnarayan.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Gautham Narayan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Gautham Narayan 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2017 00:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://gnarayan.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Gautham Narayan</title>
      <link>https://gnarayan.github.io/home/hero/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gnarayan.github.io/home/hero/</guid>
      <description>AI, Big Data, Cosmology</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://gnarayan.github.io/home/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gnarayan.github.io/home/about/</guid>
      <description>Biography Gautham Narayan is the Barry M. Lasker Data Science Fellow at STScI. His research interests lie at the intersection of multi-messenger and time-domain astrophysics, cosmology, statistics and data science. He works on wide-field surveys developing machine learning methods for real-time detection and classification of variable and transient sources, Bayesian models for cosmological inference with type Ia supernovae, and establishing an all-sky network of faint spectrophotometric standards for LSST, WFIRST and future projects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Experience</title>
      <link>https://gnarayan.github.io/home/experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gnarayan.github.io/home/experience/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research</title>
      <link>https://gnarayan.github.io/home/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gnarayan.github.io/home/projects/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://gnarayan.github.io/home/hero_carousel/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gnarayan.github.io/home/hero_carousel/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching</title>
      <link>https://gnarayan.github.io/home/teaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gnarayan.github.io/home/teaching/</guid>
      <description>I have been an instructor at the:
 ZTF Summer School, Pasadena, Aug. 2018 LSST Data Science Fellowship Program, Session 5, Baltimore, Jan. 2018 LSST Data Science Fellowship Program, Session 3, Tucson, Apr. 2017 NOAO Teen Astronomy Cafe, How Stars Die, Tucson, Nov. 2017 NOAO Big Data Workshop for Tucson High School Students, Jan. 2017 Python Workshop for NOAO/NSO REU Students, Tucson, 2014 &amp;amp; 2015 Teaching Fellow/Teaching Assistant/Tutor for introductory physics and astrophysics classes, electronics, and experimental physics  Please see my CV for a list of students I have mentored.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recent Talks</title>
      <link>https://gnarayan.github.io/home/talks_selected/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gnarayan.github.io/home/talks_selected/</guid>
      <description> Probing Supernovae Progenitors with Early-time Light Curves from K2    The Lives and Deaths of Stars, Youth For Astronomy and Engineering    ANTARES - Coping with Streaming Data, LSST Data Science Fellowship Program Session 3     </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Search</title>
      <link>https://gnarayan.github.io/home/search/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gnarayan.github.io/home/search/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://gnarayan.github.io/home/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gnarayan.github.io/home/contact/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deep Learning for Multimessenger Astrophysics</title>
      <link>https://gnarayan.github.io/project/01mlmma/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gnarayan.github.io/project/01mlmma/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m using techniques at the forefront of AI research to classify real-time data from wide-field surveys. My goal is to identify rare and unusual sources within these multi-messenger alert streams, as well as create pure samples of type Ia supernovae for cosmology with LSST. I use a combination of ML techniques to accomplish this including random forests, gradient boosting and much else. These days though, I&amp;rsquo;m using neural networks, particularly recurrent neural networks (RNNs) with Gated Recurrent Units (GRUs) or Long-Short Term Memory (LSTM) layers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forensics on Stellar Corpses</title>
      <link>https://gnarayan.github.io/project/02snia/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gnarayan.github.io/project/02snia/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m part of the KEGS team investigating the progenitor systems of supernovae with high-cadence light curves from Kepler. We&amp;rsquo;ve found some of the first supernovae that have early-time excess flux, indicating a possible main sequence companion, or surface nickel mixing. I&amp;rsquo;m leading the analysis of one of the KEGS SNIa, and I am advising a student on their analysis of an unusual rapid transient. I&amp;rsquo;ll be applying the lessons learned from Kepler to TESS, NASA&amp;rsquo;s next flagship exoplanet mission.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Standards for Future Surveys</title>
      <link>https://gnarayan.github.io/project/03calib/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gnarayan.github.io/project/03calib/</guid>
      <description>I lead the analysis of a multi-cycle HST program to establish faint (16.5 &amp;lt; V &amp;lt; 19) DA white dwarf stars as spectrophotometric standards. I developed a Bayesian method to coherently model spectroscopy and photometry, inferring SEDs tied to HST&amp;rsquo;s CALSPEC standards. These standards are within the dynamic range of upcoming wide-field facilities, particularly JWST and WFIRST, where the CALSPEC standards will saturate detectors. Observing them will result in the most accurately measured light curves ever.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Equation of State of Dark Energy</title>
      <link>https://gnarayan.github.io/project/04cosmo/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gnarayan.github.io/project/04cosmo/</guid>
      <description>Since the discovery of the accelerating expansion of the Universe in 1998, type Ia supernovae (SN Ia) have remained our most sensitive probe of dark energy. I joined the ESSENCE (Equation of State: SupErNova tracE Cosmic Expansion) project at the start of my graduate studies. ESSENCE observed over 200 SN Ia over seven years, in R and I at a median redshift of 0.4, and constrain the equation of state of dark energy, w, to 10%.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>