<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Wide-field Surveys on Gautham Narayan</title>
    <link>https://gnarayan.github.io/tags/wide-field-surveys/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Wide-field Surveys on Gautham Narayan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Gautham Narayan 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 00:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://gnarayan.github.io/tags/wide-field-surveys/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Deep Learning for Multimessenger Astrophysics</title>
      <link>https://gnarayan.github.io/project/01mlmma/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gnarayan.github.io/project/01mlmma/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m using techniques at the forefront of AI research to classify real-time data from wide-field surveys. My goal is to identify rare and unusual sources within these multi-messenger alert streams, as well as create pure samples of type Ia supernovae for cosmology with LSST. I use a combination of ML techniques to accomplish this including random forests, gradient boosting and much else. These days though, I&amp;rsquo;m using neural networks, particularly recurrent neural networks (RNNs) with Gated Recurrent Units (GRUs) or Long-Short Term Memory (LSTM) layers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Standards for Future Surveys</title>
      <link>https://gnarayan.github.io/project/03calib/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gnarayan.github.io/project/03calib/</guid>
      <description>I lead the analysis of a multi-cycle HST program to establish faint (16.5 &amp;lt; V &amp;lt; 19) DA white dwarf stars as spectrophotometric standards. I developed a Bayesian method to coherently model spectroscopy and photometry, inferring SEDs tied to HST&amp;rsquo;s CALSPEC standards. These standards are within the dynamic range of upcoming wide-field facilities, particularly JWST and WFIRST, where the CALSPEC standards will saturate detectors. Observing them will result in the most accurately measured light curves ever.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Equation of State of Dark Energy</title>
      <link>https://gnarayan.github.io/project/04cosmo/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gnarayan.github.io/project/04cosmo/</guid>
      <description>Since the discovery of the accelerating expansion of the Universe in 1998, type Ia supernovae (SN Ia) have remained our most sensitive probe of dark energy. I joined the ESSENCE (Equation of State: SupErNova tracE Cosmic Expansion) project at the start of my graduate studies. ESSENCE observed over 200 SN Ia over seven years, in R and I at a median redshift of 0.4, and constrain the equation of state of dark energy, w, to 10%.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>